Jasmeer Sangha

Brampton, Ontario | (647) 703-3049 | jasmeersangha@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasmeer-sangha/ | https://github.com/JasmeerSangha

STATEMENT

Trained astrophysicist anxious to apply attained skills in full time data science position. Extensive knowledge in Python along with other programming languages. Five plus years of experience in research and education of STEM disciplines. Awaiting opportunity to apply experience in research and satiate need for new, challenging projects concerning data science and analysis.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto SCS | August 2020

- Data Analytics Bootcamp
- Example of work: https://github.com/JasmeerSangha

York University | 2016-2018

- Masters of Science in Astrophysics
- Acquired skills: statistical modelling, technical writing, data visualization, disseminating scientific information
- Example of work (thesis): https://yorkspace.library.yorku.ca/xmlui/handle/10315/35594

University of Toronto | 2012-2016

- Honours Bachelors of Science in Physics, Astronomy and Mathematics
- Soft skills: problem solving, critical thinking

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Data Manipulation: Python(pandas, numpy, scipy), Matlab, API interactions, ETL
- Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Tableau
- <u>Database Management</u>: postgreSQL, Excel (VBA, Macros, Pivot Tables), MongoDB
- Google Suite: Analytics, Sheets, Slides, Docs, Drive
- Microsoft Suite: Excel, Word, Powerpoint, Publisher

WORK EXPERIENCE

STEM Teacher | SuOn Academy | 2018 - Present

- Communicating concepts in math, physics and computer science to students on a daily basis.
- Developed the ability to read an individual's comprehension of concepts in order to tailor lessons to benefit individuals while still being useful to an entire classroom
- Multiple students finishing in the 95th percentile in annual Waterloo math contests

Researcher | YorkU, UofT | 2015 - 2018

- Retrieval and interpretation of online data sources from published works
- Combined and enhanced codes using MATLAB, Python and Fortran to create models, visualized with Matplotlib
- Presentation and thesis created with said research resulting

Course Coordinator/Teaching Assistant | York University, UofT | 2015 - 2018

- Assisting students in groups ranging from 10 to 500 regarding course work
- Led weekly laboratories putting key physical concepts into practice